<?xml version='1.0' encoding='iso-8859-1' ?>
<!-- File Name: COURSESECTIONS.xml -->
<ROOT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>GLASS</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32232</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1006-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF GLASS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Since its chance discovery millennia ago, glass has developed into an integral and ubiquitous part of daily life. Through lectures, student presentations and field trips to the RISD museum and/or local glass studios, this course is designed to introduce students to the various ways this quixotic material has been made, used, and thought about across time. This survey course employs a chronological format and methodologies of art history, history of science, and material culture to investigate the range of glass objects, formulae, and production methods in use since glass' earliest manufacture through the mid-twentieth century. We will also examine the broader social and cultural contexts in which glass was made and explore the following themes as they relate to the history of glass: mimesis, clarity, innovation, reflection, light, and science. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt;Major requirement; junior BFA.GLASS students &lt;BR&gt;Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability and permission of Instructor. &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596241</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LITERARY ARTS AND STUDIES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26086</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1009-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ACTING WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Taught by a working professional actor/director, this introduction to acting will lead the beginning student through the artistic process involved in acting for the stage and other media. Through exercises, study of technique, scene work and improvisation, the student will work to develop natural abilities and will become familiar with the working language and tools of the modern actor.  Emphasis in this class will be on the physical self, mental preparation, the imagination, and discipline.  Written work will include keeping a journal and writing a character analysis.  Perfect attendance in this course is vital and mandatory.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomore and above.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0103295</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>INTERIOR ARCHITECTURE</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26181</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1017-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF INTERIOR ARCHITECTURE I: 1400-1850</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course will examine personalities working in Europe and in North America as well as non-western regions in the period 1400 to 2009. Areas of study will include an examination of interior architecture related issues that will be studied in the context of their social, political, technological, and economic circumstances, as they pertain to the design culture of the period. Special emphasis will be given to interior additions and renovations and other interventions. Other areas of study will include the development of architectural drawing, and the way in which designs often evolved through committees, or ongoing consultations among patrons, designers, administrators, and scholars. Attention will also be given to design theory, and the doctrines relating to site, orientation, proportion, decorum, and the commercial design market. A general background in the history of art and design is desirable but not mandatory. &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Major Requirement: BFA &lt;br&gt; INTAR majors only. &lt;br&gt; Art History credit for INTAR majors. &lt;br&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability and permission of Instructor.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>ARCHITECTURE</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>28055</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1022-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>MODERN ARCHITECTURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The course will focus on the diverse new roles encountered by the architect in the 20th century: form maker, administrator of urban development, social theorist, cultural interpreter, ideologue. Emphasis will be placed upon the increasing interdependence of architecture and the city, and the recurrent conflicts between mind and hand, modernity and locality, expressionism and universality. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt; Major requirement; Architecture majors &lt;BR&gt; Art History credit for Architecture majors &lt;BR&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability. &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1365401</COURSEFACULTY>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1598135</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>ILLUSTRATION</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26048</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1030-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF ILLUSTRATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course surveys the history of western illustration from illuminated manuscripts through approximately 2000 AD. The work shown is culled from a vast cache of artistic production for its power to convey ideas and ideals, report and editorialize events or serve as an enhancement to literature. We consider how evolving technologies in printing and communication have influenced artistic processes, shaped aesthetics and facilitated the distribution of illustration. Emphasis is placed on Illustration's role in reflecting and influencing culture, and its variable relationship to fine art. Each session includes a lecture to which students respond with show critical writing or discussions. Additionally there are weekly readings, a research project, quizzes and a final exam. Textbook required. Books will be on reserve at the RISD Library and available for purchase at a student discount. Study images are made available on RISD Digication.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Major requirement; restricted to sophomore Illustration majors; open to non-majors pending seat availability and permission of instructor.  Registration by Illustration Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1592734</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26049</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1030-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF ILLUSTRATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course surveys the history of western illustration from illuminated manuscripts through approximately 2000 AD. The work shown is culled from a vast cache of artistic production for its power to convey ideas and ideals, report and editorialize events or serve as an enhancement to literature. We consider how evolving technologies in printing and communication have influenced artistic processes, shaped aesthetics and facilitated the distribution of illustration. Emphasis is placed on Illustration's role in reflecting and influencing culture, and its variable relationship to fine art. Each session includes a lecture to which students respond with show critical writing or discussions. Additionally there are weekly readings, a research project, quizzes and a final exam. Textbook required. Books will be on reserve at the RISD Library and available for purchase at a student discount. Study images are made available on RISD Digication.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Major requirement; restricted to sophomore Illustration majors; open to non-majors pending seat availability and permission of instructor.  Registration by Illustration Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1592734</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31976</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1030-03</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF ILLUSTRATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course surveys the history of western illustration from illuminated manuscripts through approximately 2000 AD. The work shown is culled from a vast cache of artistic production for its power to convey ideas and ideals, report and editorialize events or serve as an enhancement to literature. We consider how evolving technologies in printing and communication have influenced artistic processes, shaped aesthetics and facilitated the distribution of illustration. Emphasis is placed on Illustration's role in reflecting and influencing culture, and its variable relationship to fine art. Each session includes a lecture to which students respond with show critical writing or discussions. Additionally there are weekly readings, a research project, quizzes and a final exam. Textbook required. Books will be on reserve at the RISD Library and available for purchase at a student discount. Study images are made available on RISD Digication.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Major requirement; restricted to sophomore Illustration majors; open to non-majors pending seat availability and permission of instructor.  Registration by Illustration Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1592734</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32374</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1030-04</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF ILLUSTRATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course surveys the history of western illustration from illuminated manuscripts through approximately 2000 AD. The work shown is culled from a vast cache of artistic production for its power to convey ideas and ideals, report and editorialize events or serve as an enhancement to literature. We consider how evolving technologies in printing and communication have influenced artistic processes, shaped aesthetics and facilitated the distribution of illustration. Emphasis is placed on Illustration's role in reflecting and influencing culture, and its variable relationship to fine art. Each session includes a lecture to which students respond with show critical writing or discussions. Additionally there are weekly readings, a research project, quizzes and a final exam. Textbook required. Books will be on reserve at the RISD Library and available for purchase at a student discount. Study images are made available on RISD Digication.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Major requirement; restricted to sophomore Illustration majors; open to non-majors pending seat availability and permission of instructor.  Registration by Illustration Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0001165</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>PHOTOGRAPHY</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26070</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1034-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORIES OF PHOTOGRAPHY I</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Part I of a two-semester course that will survey major topics in the Histories of Photography. Emphasis will be given to the diverse cultural uses of photography from its invention to the present day.  Such uses include: the illustrated press; amateur photography; studio photography; industrial, advertising, and fashion photography; political and social propaganda; educational and documentary photography; and photography as a medium of  artistic expression.  Much attention will be paid to how photographs construct histories, as well as being constructed by them.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Major requirement; Photo majors&lt;br&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0906862</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>APPAREL DESIGN</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26026</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1035-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF DRESS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This class examines fashion in Europe and America from the eighteenth century to the present, covering the industrial revolution through the development of couture and postmodern fashion. It analyzes clothing as a social and cultural artifact, central to the construction of group and individual identity. Lectures and readings explore the production, consumption, use and meanings of dress, and will be supplemented by visits to the RISD museum. Course work will be comprised of group and independent research, written papers, and oral presentations.  &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt; Major requirement; Apparel Design sophomores &lt;BR&gt; Art History credit for Apparel Design majors &lt;BR&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability and permission of Instructor. &lt;BR&gt; Registration by Apparel Design Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000386</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LANDSCAPE ARCHITECTURE</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26059</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1044-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF LANDSCAPE ARCHITECTURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This survey course focuses on the history of landscapes in the pre-industrialized world. Landscapes will be considered as an evolving condition, even when their defining characteristics were conceived and built at a specific point in time.  Critical to this course will be the establishment of frameworks for historical inquiry, the refinement of research methodologies, in the development of multiple perspectives through which to question and understand the design environment. &lt;br&gt; &lt;I&gt; Permission of Instructor required.  &lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>GR</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LITERARY ARTS AND STUDIES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29797</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1047-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>WITH A PEN OF LIGHT</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Hollywood films:  how are they "written" by directors, performers, scriptcrafters, cameramen and producers?  We will view a selection of films featuring directors who stamped Hollywood and us with their visions, often from other cultures.  We will also study the direction Hollywood took in interpreting the Depression, War, and Recovery, and the direction stars, writers and designers chose in defining themselves.  This is a course in criticism, history and articulate appreciation.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0004008</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>FILM/ANIMATION/VIDEO</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26027</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1054-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>TIME, LIGHT AND SOUND</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course is designed as an introduction to the 113-year history of the projected moving image (film, animation, and video). Artistic expression in these forms will be emphasized. Students discover new areas of interest while watching carefully selected examples of films and videos. During all classes, students will view films representing different styles and periods of filmmaking. About half of the classes are devoted to contemporary films. Critical thinking will be encouraged and fostered during classroom discussions. Clear expression of these thoughts will be developed through assigned readings and weekly writing assignments. During the semester, students learn about specific artists, schools of filmmaking, genres, and fields within the history of the film, animation, and video. Students also develop a common language by learning the meaning and proper usage of a glossary of common film terms. At select classes, film artists are present to introduce and discuss their work. Other guests include improvisational musicians who accompany silent films. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt; Major requirement; FAV majors &lt;BR&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability and permission of Instructor.  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0496366</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>HIST/PHIL/SO SC DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29736</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-2403-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>NCSS CORE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>In the NCSS Core Seminar, students explore key issues in nature-culture-sustainability studies, developing an inter-disciplinary understanding of the need for integrative approaches to issues including mobility and infrastructure, environmental justice and equity, sustainable food and water systems and the very real present and future of climate change. Beginning with definitions of "nature" and natural systems, drawn from environmental literature and history, we will dig into questions of what we mean by "culture" and "sustainability".   The vitality of the ecologic and social and built environment upon which we all depend will form the core of our investigations. How and where we live matters; in the present Anthropocene, questions of resiliency and adaptation take on ever greater urgency.  We will study contemporary conditions with examples from across the globe, with an eye to understanding how innovation and creative practices in art and design impact future planetary health. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  This course lays the foundation for students pursuing the NCSS concentration. The seminar will include lectures and discussions of readings and case studies. Occasional guests will include scientists, designers and others engaged at the forefront of environmental activism and research.  Students may ground their final course project in a topic connected to their own work, relating it to their major or another concentration, in addition to NCSS.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomores and juniors. &lt;br&gt; Also offered as IDISC-2403; Register in the course for which credit is desired.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0019743</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>FILM/ANIMATION/VIDEO</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32174</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-4599-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>COMMUNICATING SCIENCE THROUGH ANIMATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This class, offered jointly by professors at RISD and Brown and in partnership with the Science Center and the Creative Mind Initiative, will explore and develop the pedagogy of using visual media to convey scientific concepts.  There is a growing library of online content but often times it is not well suited for seamless adoption into educational use. The goal of this course will be to assess the quality of existing material and design new material that not only fills an educational need but makes science engaging and accessible.  Class will be comprised of lectures, labs, screenings, discussions, critiques and guest speakers.  After an introduction to science teaching pedagogy and the basics of animation and visual design, small student teams with a balance of science and art backgrounds will collaborate on a series of short exercises leading to the creation of final videos or animations that explain scientific concepts.  Topic selection will be based on filling an educational need, where a satisfactory example does not yet exist and where the topic benefits from a visual presentation. Student groups will be paired with faculty mentors from the life or physical sciences to design an educational tool that is appropriate for a particular audience.  Projects will be evaluated on accuracy, clarity of explanation, educational value, engagement with the viewer, and creativity. The skills of lesson plan design along with writing, recording, animating and editing short educational videos will give students experience within the growing field of supplements to traditional learning and online learning. &lt;BR&gt; Estimated Materials Cost: $25.00 &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt; Permission of Instructor required.  &lt;BR&gt; Also offered as FAV-4599; Register in the course for which credit is desired.  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0148646</COURSEFACULTY>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>HIST/PHIL/SO SC DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26101</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8900-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAEL INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LA ELECTIVE DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26102</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8960-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>PROFESSIONAL INTERNSHIP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The professional Internship provides valuable exposure to a professional setting, enabling students to better establish a career path and define practical aspirations. Internship proposals are carefully vetted to determine legitimacy and must meet the contact hour requirements listed in the RISD Course Announcement.&lt;br&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>HIST/PHIL/SO SC DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26103</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8965-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>COLLABORATIVE STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>A Collaborative Study Project (CSP) allows two students to work collaboratively to complete a faculty supervised project of independent study. &lt;br&gt; Usually, a CSP is supervised by two faculty members, but with approval it may be supervised by one faculty member. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses, though it is not a substitute for a course if that course is regularly offered.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LITERARY ARTS AND STUDIES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>25965</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8900-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAS INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of Instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>25967</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8960-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>PROFESSIONAL INTERNSHIP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The professional Internship provides valuable exposure to a professional setting, enabling students to better establish a career path and define practical aspirations. Internship proposals are carefully vetted to determine legitimacy and must meet the contact hour requirements listed in the RISD Course Announcement.&lt;br&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>25966</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8965-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>COLLABORATIVE STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>A Collaborative Study Project (CSP) allows two students to work collaboratively to complete a faculty supervised project of independent study. &lt;br&gt; Usually, a CSP is supervised by two faculty members, but with approval it may be supervised by one faculty member. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses, though it is not a substitute for a course if that course is regularly offered.  </COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19084</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0816254</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19085</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0303681</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19089</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-03</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0303681</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19090</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-04</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0452503</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19091</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-05</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19092</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-06</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19093</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-07</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0990901</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19094</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-08</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0990940</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19095</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-09</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623109</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19096</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-10</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623109</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19097</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-11</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623109</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19098</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-12</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1542764</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19099</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-13</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1542764</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19100</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-14</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0829447</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19101</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-15</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0829447</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19102</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-16</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000088</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19103</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-17</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000088</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19104</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-18</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596170</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19105</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-19</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596170</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19106</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-20</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000084</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19107</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-21</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596171</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19108</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-22</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0709288</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19109</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-23</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000177</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19110</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-24</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000218</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19111</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-25</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0937407</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19112</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-26</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1425658</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19113</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-27</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000073</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19535</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-28</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1598038</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>23189</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-29</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0709283</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24897</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-30</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596127</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24898</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-31</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1598038</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>28909</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-32</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596171</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32023</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E151-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ANALYSIS OF FILM NARRATIVE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course will provide an introduction to narrative theory as it relates to the visual and time arts in the production of both documentary and fiction films.  We will consider various narrative genres as well as the range of film narrative forms from Classical Hollywood to Contemporary Independent to Avant-Garde.  To fully understand the practical narrative possibilities of film's technology, we will spend some time in class analyzing and writing adaptations of literature (short stories, poems, performance monologues, novels) for film. Requirements include film screenings; reading from theoretical works, literature, and screenplays; and writing both analytical and practical exercises.  There will be an additional screening time scheduled.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0709288</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24130</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E211-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>MEDIEVAL TO EIGHTEENTH-CENTURY BRITISH LITERATURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This discussion-based course surveys major and minor works of British literature, mostly poetry, from the late Middle Ages to the Eighteenth Century, with emphasis on the way these works relate to broad cultural phenomena in other areas, including philosophy, theology, and visual arts.  Regular homework emphasizes independent critical and investigative reading of complex texts and images; formal writing assignments develop your ability to combine your own insights with those gained from casual and scholarly research, open-book midterm and final exams allow you to demonstrate your ability to analyze unfamiliar works and place them in context with those we have studied.  Readings include (mostly short) works by Chaucer (3 &lt;i&gt;Canterbury Tales&lt;/i&gt;), Spenser, Sidney, Shakespeare (Sonnets and&lt;i&gt;The Tempest&lt;/i&gt; ), Donne, Marvell, Herbert, Herrick, Milton, Bunyan, Butler, Behn, Rochester, Locke, Dryden, Pope, Hogarth, Gray, Boswell and Johnson.  </COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0303681</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32024</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E239-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>MATERIAL POETICS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Like theatre and music, poetry requires presenting the body -- particularly the voice -- to the live audience. Unlike theatre and even music, it is the writer's body that is presented, not that of an actor or performer. This makes for an interesting situation: Poetry is simultaneously a consummately conceptual and material art (and the bridging can be awkward). Poetry is language's own art form but equally, it is concerned with breath, speech, tone, tempo: the discursive sonic range of the human vocal apparatus. This investment in the body transmits to the fascination poets have for technologies of writing: manuscript/print/digital; hand/machine; public/personal. Poetry, though it has a conservative function, is definitively avant-garde and committed to articulating the new -- in terms of subject matter, form, and technology. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;br&gt; This course examines poetic traditions that cherish the material properties of poetry, whether relating to the body; to book/laptop/phone (all technologies held close to the body); or to more macro or micro dimensional surfaces or instruments -- in the garden, on the billboard, cut into the land mass, or planted within the body, whether as a biosensor inside a human or in the genome of a bacterium. We will pay special attention to voice; color; text/image and sound/image relationships; the poetry of visual artists and the visual art of poets; audience; and contemporary digital opportunity. Students will engage in creative, critical, and research projects, with particular emphasis on their own languages, cultural contexts, and poetic traditions. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt; Texts and references may include: Lady Su Hui'shuiwen (4th Century CE), William Blake's&lt;I&gt; The Marriage of Heaven and Hell &lt;I&gt; (1793), the poetry and letters of Gerard ManleyHopkins (1844 -1889), Gertrude Stein's&lt;I&gt; Tender Buttons &lt;I&gt; (1914), Kurt Schwitters&lt;I&gt; Ur Sonata &lt;I&gt; (1922-1932), The Four Horsemen (1972 to 1988), Xu Bing's&lt;I&gt; Book from the Sky &lt;I&gt; (1988) and&lt;I&gt; Book from the Ground &lt;I&gt; (2013), Kamau Brathwaite's&lt;I&gt; Trench Town Rock &lt;I&gt; (1994), David Batchelor's&lt;I&gt; Chromophobia &lt;I&gt;(2000), Johanna Drucker's &lt;I&gt;The Century of Artists' Books &lt;I&gt;(2004), Etel Adnan's&lt;I&gt; The Arab Apocalypse &lt;I&gt; (2007), Tim Ingold's&lt;I&gt; Lines &lt;I&gt;(2007), M. NourbeSe Philip's&lt;I&gt; Zong! &lt;I&gt; (2008), Jen Bervin and Martha Werner's &lt;I&gt;The Gorgeous Nothings: Emily Dickinson's Envelope Poems &lt;I&gt; (2012), Claudia Rankine's&lt;I&gt; Citizen: An American Lyric &lt;I&gt; (2014), Jen Bervin's&lt;I&gt; Silk Poems &lt;I&gt; (2017), Francesca Capone's&lt;I&gt; Weaving Language: Language is Image, Paper, Code &amp; Cloth &lt;I&gt; (2018),Giorgio de Chirico/Stefania Heim's&lt;I&gt; Geometry of Shadows &lt;I&gt; (2019), David Jhave Johnston's&lt;I&gt; ReRites &lt;I&gt; (2019), Tim Robinson's&lt;I&gt; Experiments on Reality &lt;I&gt; (2019), Christian Bk's&lt;I&gt; The Xenotext Project &lt;I&gt; (ongoing), and Ian Hamilton Finlay's &lt;I&gt; Little Sparta &lt;I&gt; (still growing). As it tends to do with all dimensions, material poetics upsets our conventions of time. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to sophomores and above.  &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0816254</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32025</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E247-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>VIRGINIA WOOLF &amp; MODERN FICTION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Students will emerge from this class with a thorough overview of Woolf's life, world, and life's work. The heart of the course will be our study of Virginia Woolf's major novels: Jacob's Room, Mrs. Dalloway, To the Lighthouse, Orlando, and The Waves. However, our reading list will also include short stories, essays, and selections from her published letters and diaries. In particular, students can expect to become skilled readers of the stream of consciousness style of narration that characterizes Woolf's fiction and to engage with themes that run through much of her writing such as the creative process, modern subjectivity, sexuality, gender, domestic space, and war.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596127</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32027</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E254-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>NATIVE AMERICAN LITERATURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Literature is one facet of culture.  The significance of literature can be best understood in terms of the culture for which it springs, and the purpose is clear only when the reader understands and accepts the assumptions on which literature is based" (Paula Gunn Allen-Laguna Sioux poet). This course will explore value systems and aesthetics that are from very diverse Native cultures, focusing on the ways in which indigenousness relates to literature and storytelling. The critical methodologies developed by Native critics such as Gerald Vizenor  (Anishinaabe writer and scholar), and Craig Womack (Muscogee Creek-Cherokee author and professor of Native Studies) will enable us to study Native frameworks and new ways to regard literature/histories. We will explore questions such as can Native American theory/literature transform or challenge non-Native critical theoretical strategies. Our discussions, which may take a variety of directions, will also examine such issues as American Indian identities and communities as well as the impact of colonization on tribal peoples.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0709283</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>25869</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E277-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>SIGNIFYING LANDSCAPES: FICTION AND FILM</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Landscapes function as apocalyptic, political, urban, imaginary, and nostalgic sites of great significance in fiction and film. Films like &lt;I&gt;Beasts of the Southern Wild, Take Shelter&lt;/I&gt;, and &lt;I&gt; Melancholia&lt;/I&gt; illustrate the environment's profound role in recent apocalyptic narratives. Cormac McCarthy's fiction in general, and the Coen Brothers' interpretation of &lt;I&gt;No Country for Old Men&lt;/I&gt; in particular, place human violence in harsh, brutal, and ancient settings. Bodies of land are divided, raped, ruined, and transformed from gardens into wastelands of abandoned machinery and landmines--as in Salman Rushdie's &lt;I&gt;Shalimar the Clown&lt;/I&gt; or Bahman Ghobadi's &lt;I&gt;Turtles Can Fly. The Garden of Evening Mists&lt;/I&gt;, by Tan Twan Eng, like Amy Waldman's &lt;I&gt;The Submission&lt;/I&gt;, places a garden at the center of the novel and its meaning. Other titles which provide an illustration of the course material include Barbara Kingsolver's &lt;I&gt;Flight Behavior&lt;/I&gt;, Krakauer and Penn's &lt;I&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/I&gt;, Dave Eggers' Zeitoun, Josh Fox's documentary &lt;I&gt;Gasland&lt;/I&gt;, Wes Anderson's nostalgic landscape in &lt;I&gt;Moonrise Kingdom&lt;/I&gt;, and imaginary places in films like &lt;I&gt;After Life&lt;/I&gt; (Kore-eda Hirokazu), &lt;I&gt;Micmacs&lt;/I&gt; (Jean-Pierre Jeunet), and &lt;I&gt;Marwencol&lt;/I&gt; (Jeff Malmberg). Titles will change each semester. Weekly writing assignments in response to the reading and films are required.&lt;BR&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32034</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E297-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>THE FICTION OF COLSON WHITEHEAD</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>In 2016, Colson Whitehead's &lt;I&gt;The Underground Railroad&lt;/I&gt; won the National Book Award and was selected for Oprah's Book Club-a pair of honors that bespeaks the critical recognition and popular appeal of his work. Since his debut novel, &lt;I&gt;The Intuitionist&lt;/I&gt; (1999), the hallmark of Whitehead's fiction has been the way in which it bridges between "highbrow" and popular culture, from noir to advertising to zombies. In this course we will consider these collisions of literary form and generic fiction, and specifically how Whitehead uses them to confront deep-rooted narratives of progress, race, and enterprise in America. Readings will include several of Whitehead's novels - &lt;I&gt;The Intuitionist, John Henry Days, Apex Hides the Hurt, Zone One, and The Underground Railroad &lt;/I&gt;- and a sampling of his essays, articles, and tweets. Students will produce several short written exercises and one final mixed-media or multi-media project that they develop over the duration of the course.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1474532</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32120</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E298-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>EMILY DICKINSON</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Emily Dickinson (1830 -1886) has an undeserved reputation for being a gloomy, inscrutable, death-obsessed recluse. But, when reading her poetry, letters, herbaria, recipes, and random notes, we come to discover a more complex figure: Dickinson was a nimble-minded, inclusive thinker; a poet obsessed with songs, riddles, and linguistic puzzles; a skilled baker; a locally admired gardener; a lover of human, animal, and natural worlds; and a playful, devoted friend. In her poetry, Dickinson could invest the same vast and inimitable creative and intellectual energies into an exploration of the fate of the human soul as she could into an observation of her cat stalking a bird. Formally, stylistically, and conceptually, her poetry defied and continues to defy convention, and it went virtually unpublished during her lifetime. Her poetry is also rare in that its interpretation depends on its visual presentation. During her life, Dickinson collected and annotated her poetry in handwritten booklets (or fascicles). These fascicles open up opportunities to appreciate her work more abstractly as visual-literary art that fundamentally challenges our expectations of what makes a poem a poem. In this course, we will read, discuss, and write about the many versions of Dickinson, as seen through the various scholarly efforts to transcribe, edit, and publish her work, as well as through our own manuscript-transcription projects. We will also explore the material, historical, biographical, and critical contexts for her work, drawing from a diverse body of meticulous, creative, and rebellious Dickinson criticism. Far from a traditional literature class, this course adopts a hands-on approach to understanding Dickinson's life and work, which will include manuscript transcription projects, natural historical excursions, bread and pastry baking efforts, along with various writing assignments and exercises. The course also includes a short trip to Amherst, Massachusetts, where we will visit the Dickinson Homestead and Museum (where Emily lived and composed the vast majority of her letters and poems), spend time in the Dickinson archives at Amherst College, and explore the surrounding town and its natural environment. &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; LAS-E101 is a prerequisite for undergraduates.  &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1545266</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32102</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E299-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>THE LESBIAN NOVEL</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>To be a lesbian, according to Monique Wittig, seems the simplest and most complex mode of desiring: "she who was interested in 'only' half of the population and had a violent desire for that half." In a world overcrowded by the voices and bodies of men, how does a lesbian carve out physical and imaginative space to let her desires free? This course will explore how this question has been addressed by daring, renegade lesbian writers who have used the medium of textual narrative to produce both history and future. Rather than reading these novels as historical document, sociological artifact, or even personal testaments, we will digest them as performance, wish-fulfillment, blueprint for a world in which love and sex between women reign. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; LAS-E101 is a prerequisite for undergraduates. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0990901</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32028</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E302-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>POSTCOLONIAL LITERATURES II: IRELAND, OCEANIA, AND THE INDIAN SUBCONTINENT</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Postcolonial literature is the writing produced by people in or from regions that have escaped the yoke of colonialism.  Of course, such a definition raises a number of questions, and during the semester we will grapple with the definition.  Our readings will open with several theoretical discussions of postcoloniality, then we will continue with novels and poetry from Australia, India, Indonesia, Ireland, New Zealand, Samoa, and Sri Lanka.  This history of trading empires and settler colonies will be a major focus in this course.  Through individual projects and a final paper that works with at least one of the theoretical texts and a novel or book of poetry, students can begin to focus on the area in the field that specifically interests them.  Writers may include Ciaran Carson, Lionel Fogarty, Keri Hulme, R.K. Narayan, Michael Ondaatje, Pramoedya Ananta Toer, and Albert Wendt.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0452503</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32029</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E309-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE> TRANSNATIONAL SPY &amp; DETECTIVE FICTION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course, besides revisiting the traditional narrative elements of spy and detective fiction, considers a selection of the increasing number of late twentieth- and twenty-first-century transnational, diasporic, postcolonial, and minority/ethnic authors from around the world who adapt spy and detective fiction conventions for the purpose of social critique. In focusing on issues related to identity, "culture," ethics, human rights, justice, and knowledge construction narrated by these fictions, we will examine carefully, for example, the figure of the spy or detective as outsider to and observer of society as well as, in the works at issue here, frequently an immigrant or cultural or social "other." In the process, we will also engage questions central to reading, interpreting, and comparing fiction in a global context.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000177</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>30471</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E325-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>WRITING THE CLIMATE CRISIS: JUSTICE, IDENTITY, AND ENVIRONMENT IN AMERICAN LITERATURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>In this course we will discover how struggles of identity and justice interact with representations of the environment in the literatures of Africana, Chicano/a, Asian, and Native American authors.  We will investigate and appraise how these authors portray nature as theme, plot, character, and setting to accomplish the environmental aims of their texts. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomores and above.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000084</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32030</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E360-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>RADICAL THEATER: BRECHT &amp; AFTER</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Fascism got you down?  Tired of endless war?  Wondering how art could possibly stand up to--let alone subvert--the predations of big-time capitalism and its police state? Unfortunately, these are not new questions.  Fortunately, they have been taken on directly by some modern dramatic innovators, among the first of whom was Bertolt Brecht (Germany, 1898-1956).   Playwright, director, theorist and provocateur, Brecht drew on popular, traditional forms, which he deployed in response to the crises of his times in order to rewrite the theatrical rulebook.  The course will study Brecht's major works along with some of his theoretical writings before looking at the legacy of Brechtian theater among diverse playwrights such as Dario Fo &amp; Franca Rame, David Hare, Caryl Churchill, Alecky Blythe, Tony Kushner, Lynn Nottage, Sarah Kane, Suzan-Lori Parks, Mark Ravenhill, Jeremy O. Harris.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0185166</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>28059</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E368-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>CINEMA AND NEW MEDIA</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Digital technologies have shaped contemporary media and culture in profound ways, including how we make, experience, and talk about art, design, commerce, and culture, bodies, identities, and communities, privacy, security, and war, time, space, and geography, and even the politics of meaning and "truth" themselves. In this course, we will look specifically to late 20th and early 21st century cinema -- ostensibly now an "old" medium -- to help us understand (and sometimes productively misunderstand) new media. What is new media and what can cinema specifically tell us about it? What has become of cinema, both culturally and structurally, under the digital? How has cinema historically represented new or emergent media technologies? How have forms of vision and perception that have emerged or intensified alongside new media -- satellites, drones, surveillance, smart phones, etc. -- troubled cinema on formal, stylistic, and epistemological levels? What kinds of new or transformative potential has new media unearthed for future cinemas? Through readings of contemporary media studies scholarship, weekly film screenings, and student presentations, we will take up these and related questions.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to sophomore and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596193</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32031</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E371-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ENVIRONMENTAL COMICS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>In this course, we will discuss how comics and other forms of literary-visual art illuminate various environmental concepts. Environmental problems are caused not merely by technological expansion or political negligence. They also result from, and persist as, problems of representation. An environmental crisis is a cultural crisis. Beginning from this position, we will consider comics art as a unique medium for telling stories about how humans and other animals relate to their environments, focusing especially on the form's capacity for representing time, space, word, and image in sequence. To further enrich our understanding of the cultural values and concepts that undergird the environmental decisions individuals, communities, and institutions make every day, we will examine how environmental problems intersect with issues of race, class, gender, sexuality, and disability. As astute environmental critics, we will dismantle the experience of reading comics, and the craft of making them, through frequent in-class discussions, creative projects, and a series of analytical assignments in both written and comics form. These assignments will help us come to understand comics art as a medium for both creative and critical invention. Throughout the semester, we will read comics in various formats and genres, including (but not limited to) graphic novels, comic strips, serialized comic books, zines, web comics, illustrated journals, manga, memoir, biography, fiction, and journalism. &lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt; Open to sophomore and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1545266</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>25837</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E411-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BEGINNING POETRY WRITING WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Beginning Poetry Workshop is an elective course introducing students to the art of poetry writing. The course sequentially addresses major commitments of poetry including form/content, sound, line, voice, image, language(s), tradition/convention, experiment, audience, revision, performance, collection, publication, and distribution. Workshop is the heart of the course, animating the practice, discourse, critique, audience, community, and mentorship vital to poets. Every class will also include close reading, discussion of assigned texts, and writing. We will attend public readings, curate and participate in community readings, and welcome poets to our class, when possible. Work can be developed in a range of styles, traditions, and languages. You will leave this class with a collection of workshopped and revised poems, which you will design, self-publish, and distribute in print and/or digital form.  &lt;BR&gt;The Beginning Poetry Workshop is a prerequisite for the LAS-E421 Advanced Poetry Workshop in the Spring. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomore and above.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0816254</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>20380</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E412-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BEGINNING FICTION WRITING WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>While the writing of fiction involves only the writer and the page, the group workshop affords the writer the opportunity to explore, develop and refine his or her work in a small community focused on a single goal. This environment of craft and creativity is particularly critical to the beginning writer. As with any craft, revision is the key to effective storytelling. The revision process will be emphasized. Short fiction by leading writers will be read and discussed; elements of craft will be explored; students will learn to deliver criticism in a supportive, constructive way; but learning by doing will comprise the majority of the class. Writing will begin in the first class, leading to small, peer-driven workshop groups and culminating in a full class workshop at semester's end. Students will produce three stories throughout the semester, all of which will be workshopped and revised. The student's engagement in the course, participation and attendance, will drive the final grades.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomore and above.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1365402</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29779</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E415-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>JOURNALISM WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Journalistic writing is an act of seeing out into the world of observable fact.  In this course, the student will be introduced to the craft of journalism, including feature articles, interviews, reporting on events, reviews and editorials.  Emphasis will be placed on the exploration of our community and the discipline of presenting the results of our quest before the public. &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomore and above.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0004008</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>19129</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E416-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>PICTURE AND WORD</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>A workshop-style course which combines English with a studio project for students with an interest in children's picture books.  Students will learn to develop storytelling skills (imagination, language, plot, character, and voice) and illustration techniques (characterization, setting, page, layout) by studying picture books and completing writing and illustration assignments.  For their final projects, students will be expected to produce an original text, sketch dummy, and two to four finished pieces of art.  The class will also include an overview of publishing procedures and published writers/illustrators will be invited to share their experiences and critique students' work. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Students must plan and register for both LAS-E416 and ILLUS-3612 and will receive 3 studio credits and 3 liberal arts credits.  &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1487493</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32210</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E423-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>CREATIVE NON-FICTION WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Creative Nonfiction can be tricky to define. While not journalism per se, creative nonfiction can incorporate historical facts or texts alongside a narrative of personal experience. Dating back to 16th century essayist Michel De Montaigne, and the arguable invention of the essai as a method of testing ideas, creative nonfiction is often a kind of organized thought experiment through personal experience. Joan Didion, James Baldwin, and Susan Sontag were exemplary figures in the 60s and 70s blending personal reflection with an examination of current events and contemporary issues. Today, such literary figures as Claudia Rankine, Jesmyn Ward, and Maggie Nelson carry on this tradition. At the heart of nonfiction, lies the examining mind that uses a sense of self or often lyrical "I" to investigate a larger world experience. We will be examining how our own personal sense of the daily and the ordinary can be used as a kind of crucible to think about, through, and with current events and other social and political happenings today.   &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000088</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32032</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E430-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LIARY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The word "liary" references the seven volumes of Anais Nin's diaries, which, upon their publication, were denounced by Nin's friends as utter fiction, as the "liary."  This course will treat this insult as the basis for a literary genre: the fiction of life itself.  We will focus on the production of liaries: fiction using real life - your own.  But rather than thinking about lived experience as the raw material of fiction which finds expression through words, we will think about words themselves as the medium through which the fiction of life can be constructed.  In this course, we will be fully invested in the materiality of words and the functionality of fiction.  We will collide with words as if they were a particularly willful batch of clay, to find different ways in which fictionality is created when a word is imagined to give contour to the slippery moments of living.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0990901</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32104</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E465-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>VERSE AFRICA: CONTEMPORARY POETRY FROM AFRICA AND THE AFRICAN DIASPORAS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>In this course we will critically engage the poetry and poetics of contemporary African, African American and Caribbean poets to examine the incredibly diverse aesthetic trends as well as their intersections. Students will produce both critical and creative responses to the texts we read and will have the opportunity to workshop their own poems influenced by the works we engage. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1595660</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32033</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E501-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FROM LITERARY TO CULTURAL STUDIES</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Cultural studies has made its mark in the humanities as a structured discipline since the 1960s. It emerged from a dissatisfaction with traditional literary criticism and sought to widen the latter's focus on aesthetic masterpieces of "high" culture by incorporating "low," popular, and mass culture in an interdisciplinary analysis of "texts," their production, distribution and consumption. Varied "texts" from the world of art, film, TV, advertising, detective novels, music, folklore, etc., as well as everyday objects, discourses, and institutions have since been discussed in their social, historical, ideological and political contexts. This course will provide an introduction to the field and its concerns.  It will also encourage students to practice some of its modes of analysis.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0937407</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>30414</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E591-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LET'S HAVE A KIKI: STORIES OF QUEER BARS AND DRAG BALLS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Kiki (n): A party including good music and good friends, held for the express purpose of calming nerves, reducing anxiety and stress and generally fighting ennui. May involve locked doors, tea and salacious gossip. This course is based on the premise that LGBT history is told through conversations about and descriptions of spaces. We will use novels, stories, poems, films, and theory to investigate how queer spaces are required to serve multiple often contradictory functions-queer bars are for drinking but also seeking healthcare resources; queer neighborhoods provide a much-needed sense of belonging while also fomenting gossip, judgmental cliques, and gentrification. The definition of the word "kiki" implies that these contradictions speak to a culturally acquired experience of anxiety and nervousness. Guiding our exploration of this anxiety will be queer theory and gender studies addressing the tension between sexual acts and identity, the closet, homophobia and transphobia, intersectionality, and queer of color critique. &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000073</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29785</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E724-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>SEM: WOMEN'S RESISTANCE ACROSS THE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This seminar explores roles women have played in wars for independence and democracy across the Global South.  As the Italian director Gillo Pontecorvo depicts in his iconic film, The Battle of Algiers (1966), some women fought alongside men carrying bombs in the fight for freedom from French imperialism in Algeria. However, more often, women have forged their own paths parallel to men enacting complex forms of resistance through art, mobilizing domesticity, and protest. Using women's participation in Algerian independence in the 1950s as our starting point, we will engage with women who resist the reductive fantasy of the bomb-carrying female freedom fighter throughout world. Figures under our investigative lens will include Assia Djebar who illustrates women playing new roles outside of the home in Algeria; women who led the peacemaking process in Liberia to bring Africa's first female president, Ellen Johnson Sirleaf, to power; and Lina Ben Mhenni who used social media in Tunisia to show the world injustice taking place under a repressive regime in 2010. Alongside these memoirs, literary texts, historical documents, and films by and about women at war, we will develop a critical vocabulary of women at work reading theorists that include Karl Marx, Michel Foucault, Gayatri Spivak, and Judith Butler. Over the course of the semester, we will put these voices in conversation with one another in order to reconstruct alternative histories of resisting oppression in the Global South and beyond.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomore and above. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020FA</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1598038</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>ARCHITECTURE</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>28056</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1005-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>WORLD ARCHITECTURE: FROM PRE-HISTORY TO PRE-MODERN: IDEAS AND ARTIFACTS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This history of architecture course, co-taught by an architectural historian and an architect, introduces key ideas, forces, and techniques that have shaped world architecture through the ages prior to the modern period. The course is based on critical categories, ranging from indigenous and vernacular architecture, to technology, culture, and representation. The lectures and discussions present systems of thought, practice and organization, emphasizing both historical and global interconnectedness, and critical architectural differences and anomalies. Each topic will be presented through case studies accompanied by relevant texts. The students will be expected to engage in the discussion groups, prepare material for these discussions, write about, and be examined on the topics. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt; Major requirement; Architecture majors &lt;BR&gt; Art History credit for Architecture majors &lt;BR&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability and permission of Instructor. &lt;BR&gt; Registration by Architecture Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1175973</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>GLASS</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26067</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1006-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF GLASS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Since its chance discovery millennia ago, glass has developed into an integral and ubiquitous part of daily life. Through lectures, student presentations and field trips to the RISD museum and/or local glass studios, this course is designed to introduce students to the various ways this quixotic material has been made, used, and thought about across time. This survey course employs a chronological format and methodologies of art history, history of science, and material culture to investigate the range of glass objects, formulae, and production methods in use since glass' earliest manufacture through the mid-twentieth century. We will also examine the broader social and cultural contexts in which glass was made and explore the following themes as they relate to the history of glass: mimesis, clarity, innovation, reflection, light, and science. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt;Major requirement; junior BFA.GLASS students &lt;BR&gt;Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability and permission of Instructor. &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596241</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LITERARY ARTS AND STUDIES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31392</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1012-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>PUBLIC PRESENTATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course, taught by a working professional actor/director with experience in stage, radio, tv and film, is centered on the belief that speaking skillfully in public is a way to self-discovery, self-improvement and self-confidence.  It is also a tenet of this course that skillful public speaking is a fundamental element of a humane society.  Students will deliver five major speeches, including self-written speeches of introduction, ceremonial speeches, informative speeches and persuasive speeches.  The oral interpretation of literature will also be explored.  Each class meeting will require every student's speaking participation in order to develop skills in the areas of voice, diction, managing speech anxiety, research and organization, use of microphones and video, and use of visual aids.  The latter phase of this course will focus on concentration, credibility, and familiarity with argument, debate and parliamentary procedure.  Attendance at each class is vital and mandatory; furthermore, students will be required to "dress up" for their presentations.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0103295</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LANDSCAPE ARCHITECTURE</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26061</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1020-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ISSUES IN LANDSCAPE HISTORY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course examines current issues raised by the design of built environments and explores the cultures, conditions, events, attitudes and design works of the past that form the ideological, physical and practical background against which today's landscapes are made, interpreted and valued. Critical to this course will be the establishment of frameworks for historical inquiry, the refinement of research methodologies, and the development of multiple perspectives through which to question and understand the designed environment. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Permission of Instructor required.  &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>GR</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0611073</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>FURNITURE DESIGN</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>30004</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1026-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF FURNITURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course is an introductory survey of the history of furniture.  An emphasis is placed on developing a methodology for understanding historical context and transferable critical thinking through furniture. The fundamental methodology presents furniture design as an expression of interdependent relationships involving technology, identity and culture. The course will include lectures, sketching, writing, discussion and exams as well as learning from direct observation of objects including many in the RISD Museum. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;I&gt;Major requirement; Furniture Design majors only. &lt;BR&gt; Art History credit for Furniture Design majors. &lt;BR&gt;  Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability and Permission of Instructor required. &lt;BR&gt; Restricted to Furniture Design majors in Spring semester. &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0009143</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>INTERIOR ARCHITECTURE</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26182</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1027-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF INTERIOR ARCHITECTURE II: 1850 to Present</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course will examine the major designers working in the period 1850 to the present.  Areas of study will include an examination of design related issues that will be studied in the context of their social, political, technological, and economic circumstances, as they pertain to the design culture of the period. Special emphasis will be given to the history of interior interventions, additions and renovations.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;br&gt; Other areas of study will include the development of architectural drawing and other presentation media, and the way in which designs often evolved through committees, or ongoing consultations among the patrons, designers, administrators, and scholars. Attention will also be given to design theory, and the doctrines relating to site, orientation, proportion, decorum, and the commercial design market.&lt;BR&gt; A general background in the history of art and design is desirable but is not mandatory. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt;Major requirement: BFA&lt;br&gt; INTAR majors only. &lt;BR&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit.&lt;br&gt; Permission of Instructor required.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1545375</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>ILLUSTRATION</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26133</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1030-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF ILLUSTRATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course surveys the history of western illustration from illuminated manuscripts through approximately 2000 AD. The work shown is culled from a vast cache of artistic production for its power to convey ideas and ideals, report and editorialize events or serve as an enhancement to literature. We consider how evolving technologies in printing and communication have influenced artistic processes, shaped aesthetics and facilitated the distribution of illustration. Emphasis is placed on Illustration's role in reflecting and influencing culture, and its variable relationship to fine art. Each session includes a lecture to which students respond with show critical writing or discussions. Additionally there are weekly readings, a research project, quizzes and a final exam. Textbook required. Books will be on reserve at the RISD Library and available for purchase at a student discount. Study images are made available on RISD Digication.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Major requirement; restricted to sophomore Illustration majors; open to non-majors pending seat availability and permission of instructor.  Registration by Illustration Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0001165</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26134</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1030-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF ILLUSTRATION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course surveys the history of western illustration from illuminated manuscripts through approximately 2000 AD. The work shown is culled from a vast cache of artistic production for its power to convey ideas and ideals, report and editorialize events or serve as an enhancement to literature. We consider how evolving technologies in printing and communication have influenced artistic processes, shaped aesthetics and facilitated the distribution of illustration. Emphasis is placed on Illustration's role in reflecting and influencing culture, and its variable relationship to fine art. Each session includes a lecture to which students respond with show critical writing or discussions. Additionally there are weekly readings, a research project, quizzes and a final exam. Textbook required. Books will be on reserve at the RISD Library and available for purchase at a student discount. Study images are made available on RISD Digication.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Major requirement; restricted to sophomore Illustration majors; open to non-majors pending seat availability and permission of instructor.  Registration by Illustration Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;br&gt;  &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0233568</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>APPAREL DESIGN</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>30200</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1036-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>TOPICS IN FASHION THEORY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>"Topics in Fashion Theory" complements the design history survey, "History of Dress." ("History of Dress" is not a prerequisite). This seminar will introduce students to theoretical debates in fashion theory, responding to scholars who define fashion as the cultural construction of embodied identity. Through the manipulation of the visual and tactile symbols of clothing (cut, cloth, texture and color) fashion expresses, however imprecisely, a configuration of individual attributes and attitudes that persons seek to communicate. But fashion most likely productively draws upon "recurrent instabilities" in collective social identities, argues Fred Davis, including masculinity versus femininity, androgyny versus singularity, license versus restraint and conformity versus rebellion. Fashion can do so because social identities are rarely the stable amalgams we take them to be: they shift over the course of a lifetime and are prodded by social and technological change. Drawing on scholarship in a range of disciplines, including sociology, cultural studies, gender studies and queer theory, we will explore clothing's role in marking, or alternately containing, deflecting or sublimating, those aspects of identity linked to gender, sexuality, class, race, religion and nation. Noting that leading designers use the catwalk to present experimental clothes that often communicate brand values and the designer's identity, we will explore the extent to which fashion is currently formulating effective social commentary. &lt;BR&gt; The class integrates reading and reading responses with discussion and visual analysis of clothing and fashion across the twentieth- and twenty-first centuries. Reading responses will help students develop four short written projects that assess and analyze debates encountered in class discussion and readings. Class time will include in-class writing and peer review. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to Apparel majors only; sophomore and above &lt;BR&gt; Open to non-majors by permission of Instructor. &lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0177244</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>INDUSTRIAL DESIGN</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26032</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1038-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF INDUSTRIAL DESIGN</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>History is a powerful tool; a basic understanding of the history of design and familiarity with important design movements and designers is essential for thorough design work. By examining the work of other designers, we are better able to identify our own interests and concerns, and avoid repeating mistakes that have been navigated in the past. This lecture-based class will present the history of Industrial Design in a way that links it to today's studio work, and offers connection points to link past innovation and design activity with future design success. The lectures present a chronological overview of the profession of Industrial Design and its antecedents. Topics discussed will include major design movements, significant designers, manufacturers, and design-related companies, innovations in technology and material use, the development of sales, marketing, and user-focused designing, and the history of design process. Coursework includes extensive reading, in-class presentations based on independent research, projects, and writing. &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Major requirement; ID majors&lt;br&gt; Registration of Industrial Design Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;Br&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0090560</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26033</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1038-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF INDUSTRIAL DESIGN</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>History is a powerful tool; a basic understanding of the history of design and familiarity with important design movements and designers is essential for thorough design work. By examining the work of other designers, we are better able to identify our own interests and concerns, and avoid repeating mistakes that have been navigated in the past. This lecture-based class will present the history of Industrial Design in a way that links it to today's studio work, and offers connection points to link past innovation and design activity with future design success. The lectures present a chronological overview of the profession of Industrial Design and its antecedents. Topics discussed will include major design movements, significant designers, manufacturers, and design-related companies, innovations in technology and material use, the development of sales, marketing, and user-focused designing, and the history of design process. Coursework includes extensive reading, in-class presentations based on independent research, projects, and writing. &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Major requirement; ID majors&lt;br&gt; Registration of Industrial Design Department, course not available via web registration. &lt;Br&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0090560</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>PHOTOGRAPHY</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26071</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1039-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORIES OF PHOTOGRAPHY II</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Part II of a two-semester course that will survey major topics in the Histories of Photography. Emphasis will be given to the diverse cultural uses of photography from its invention to the present day.  Such uses include: the illustrated press; amateur photography; studio photography; industrial; advertising, and fashion photography; political and social propaganda; educational and documentary photography; and photography as a medium of artistic expression.  Much attention will be paid to how photographs construct histories, as well as being constructed by them.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Major requirement; Photo majors&lt;br&gt; Liberal Arts elective credit for non-majors pending seat availability.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1485333</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>TEXTILES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26072</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-1082-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>HISTORY OF WESTERN TEXTILES: FOCUS ON EUROPE AND AMERICA</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>By way of illustrated lecture (both in the classroom and at the Museum), discussions and readings, students will come to understand the stylistic and cultural significance of textiles in relation to the history of Western art, design, and fashion from the middle ages to the modern era. Topics covered will included Italian Renaissance trade silks and tapestries, Rococo patterned silks and laces, printed textiles of the Arts and Crafts movement, and important artist / designer textile collaborations of the twentieth century.  Additionally, the course with define historicism and investigate historical revivals as used by contemporary textile designers. The manner in which social, economic, technological, and political changes have impacted advancements in textile fibers, fabric structures, color, and design will be emphasized. Term projects utilizing art historical and material culture studies afford students the opportunity to gain valuable research skills and explore history as a rich source of design inspiration.  &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Textiles majors can be pre-registered by the department.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1550937</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>ARCHITECT. &amp; DESIGN</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>30111</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-2012-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>CLIMATE CHANGE AND NATURAL HAZARDS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Landscape architects and designers in other disciplines are taking an increasingly important role in addressing complex questions related to climate change and natural hazards.  These questions involve intersecting cultural and scientific issues.  This course is designed to equip landscape architects and other designers with an essential foundation in physical and social scientific aspects of climate change so that they may better engage with these questions.  Although it is impossible to cover the breadth of necessary topics and issues in a single semester, students will learn to analyze and access the scientific literature so that they can individually extend their education.   &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Emphasis will also be placed on essential skills and disciplinary approaches to enable more effective collaboration in interdisciplinary and transdisciplinary contexts.  This includes addressing cultural and disciplinary differences in approaches to scientific concepts such as validity and uncertainty, and examining epistemological aspects of science.  This course is an essential primer in climate change and natural hazards for any student who hopes to address these issues in their work or to work in policy based contexts. &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open undergraduates only; sophomore and above.  &lt;BR&gt; Also offered as IDISC-2012; Register in the course for which credit is desired.  &lt;/i&gt;  </COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0194134</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>HIST/PHIL/SO SC DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29737</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-2403-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>NCSS CORE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>In the NCSS Core Seminar, students explore key issues in nature-culture-sustainability studies, developing an inter-disciplinary understanding of the need for integrative approaches to issues including mobility and infrastructure, environmental justice and equity, sustainable food and water systems and the very real present and future of climate change. Beginning with definitions of "nature" and natural systems, drawn from environmental literature and history, we will dig into questions of what we mean by "culture" and "sustainability".   The vitality of the ecologic and social and built environment upon which we all depend will form the core of our investigations. How and where we live matters; in the present Anthropocene, questions of resiliency and adaptation take on ever greater urgency.  We will study contemporary conditions with examples from across the globe, with an eye to understanding how innovation and creative practices in art and design impact future planetary health. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;  This course lays the foundation for students pursuing the NCSS concentration. The seminar will include lectures and discussions of readings and case studies. Occasional guests will include scientists, designers and others engaged at the forefront of environmental activism and research.  Students may ground their final course project in a topic connected to their own work, relating it to their major or another concentration, in addition to NCSS.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomores and juniors. &lt;br&gt; Also offered as IDISC-2403; Register in the course for which credit is desired.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0019743</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LA ELECTIVE DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31742</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8800-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN UNIVERSITY COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31743</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8800-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN UNIVERSITY COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31920</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8888-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN DUAL-DEGREE COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31921</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8888-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN DUAL-DEGREE COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31922</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8888-03</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN DUAL-DEGREE COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31923</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8888-04</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN DUAL-DEGREE COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LITERARY ARTS AND STUDIES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31692</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8900-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAEL INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1425658</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>HISTORY OF ART&amp;VISUAL CULTURE</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31949</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8900-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAEL INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1446195</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>HIST/PHIL/SO SC DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31972</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-8900-03</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAEL INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0019743</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LA ELECTIVE DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31379</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-9200-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>EHP ITALIAN</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course is designed for beginners in Italian and provides an introduction to the basic structures of the language and to Italian culture. Throughout the course, situations that often represent obstacles to newcomers to Italy are presented to assist students in learning how to immerse themselves into a new country and a new culture. Vocabulary and grammar are presented through teaching materials-including listening comprehensions, and the reading of Italian texts-which refer to situations relevant to the students' experience in Italy.  The study of the Italian language is integrated with an overview of contemporary Italian culture through films, music and lectures that deal with cultural topics. Students will be asked to perform role-plays, street assignments and discussions in order to enable them to speak and interact in Italian. Students are expected to participate actively in the class discussions and activities, and to contribute with suggestions, ideas and presentations &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open only to students studying in Rome in the RISD EHP Program&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0526386</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LITERARY ARTS AND STUDIES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31745</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8800-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN UNIVERSITY COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31874</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8800-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN UNIVERSITY COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31926</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8888-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN DUAL-DEGREE COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31927</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8888-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN DUAL-DEGREE COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31934</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8888-03</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BROWN DUAL-DEGREE COURSE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC></COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31708</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8900-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAS INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of Instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1425658</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31710</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8900-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAS INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of Instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1541782</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LA ELECTIVE DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31875</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8900-03</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAS INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of Instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1153038</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>HIST/PHIL/SO SC DEPT</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31938</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8900-04</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAS INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of Instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0044728</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>THEORY &amp; HISTORY ART &amp; DESIGN</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31941</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-8900-05</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LAS INDEPENDENT STUDY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Independent Study Project (ISP) allows students to supplement the established curriculum by completing a faculty supervised project for credit in a specific area of interest. Its purpose is to meet individual student needs by providing an alternative to regularly offered courses.&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Permission of Instructor and GPA of 3.0 or higher is required.&lt;BR&gt; Register by completing the Independent Study Application available on the Registrar's website; the course is not available via web registration. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1446195</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
<DEPARTMENT>
 <NAME>LITERARY ARTS AND STUDIES</NAME>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24143</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596171</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24144</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0829447</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24145</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E101-03</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FIRST-YEAR LITERATURE SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>An introduction to literary study that helps students develop the skills necessary for college-level reading, writing, research and critical thinking. Through exposure to a variety of literary forms and genres, historical periods and critical approaches, students are taught how to read closely, argue effectively and develop a strong writing voice. The course is reading and writing intensive and organized around weekly assignments.&lt;br&gt; Required for graduation for all undergraduates, including transfers. There are no waivers for LAS-E101 except for transfer students who have taken an equivalent college course.&lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; For the Fall semester, freshmen are pre-registered into this course. &lt;br&gt; Please contact the department concerning any registration questions.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1425658</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29782</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E209-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>EPIC</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Epic narratives seem antagonistically devoted to their predecessors in the genre and to the cultural mythologies of their own times. Students in this course will read a series of epics written from antiquity to the present and consider as well the genre's incursions into film.  Texts might include:  Homer's &lt;i&gt;Iliad or Odyssey&lt;/i&gt;, Virgil's &lt;i&gt;Aeneid&lt;/i&gt;, Dante's &lt;i&gt;Inferno&lt;/i&gt;, and Walcott's &lt;i&gt;Omeros&lt;/i&gt;. There will be midterm and final examinations, an independently researched essay, and regular short writing assignments. &lt;br&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0185166</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29786</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E209-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>EPIC</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Epic narratives seem antagonistically devoted to their predecessors in the genre and to the cultural mythologies of their own times. Students in this course will read a series of epics written from antiquity to the present and consider as well the genre's incursions into film.  Texts might include:  Homer's &lt;i&gt;Iliad or Odyssey&lt;/i&gt;, Virgil's &lt;i&gt;Aeneid&lt;/i&gt;, Dante's &lt;i&gt;Inferno&lt;/i&gt;, and Walcott's &lt;i&gt;Omeros&lt;/i&gt;. There will be midterm and final examinations, an independently researched essay, and regular short writing assignments. &lt;br&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0185166</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29798</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E237-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>CONTEMPORARY POETRY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course identifies and focuses on key practices in contemporary poetry including Spoken Word, Digital Language Arts, translation, and hybrid or twinned publication between page and screen. Spoken Word speaks to the origins of poetry in public performance. Digital Language Arts open up the funfair of color, animation and sound which print closed down, while also seizing back self-publication --and distribution on an unprecedented scale. Multiplicity seems more apt than singularity today. We are more or less obliged to work across media, disciplines, languages, and political boundaries, and to present work in multiple forms. It's a time of both/and rather than either/or. We will discuss and write about a range of contemporary print, digital, and performance works; students will also compose and publish/perform at least one single-authored or collaborative poem. Contemporary Poetry is one of a set of multimodal courses including Sound Poetry, Visual Poetry, Digital Poetics, and Material Poetics, investigating sensory and material poetic traditions in contemporary culture. All courses have creative, critical, research, and performance/publication commitments. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomore and above&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0816254</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29799</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E237-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>CONTEMPORARY POETRY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course identifies and focuses on key practices in contemporary poetry including Spoken Word, Digital Language Arts, translation, and hybrid or twinned publication between page and screen. Spoken Word speaks to the origins of poetry in public performance. Digital Language Arts open up the funfair of color, animation and sound which print closed down, while also seizing back self-publication --and distribution on an unprecedented scale. Multiplicity seems more apt than singularity today. We are more or less obliged to work across media, disciplines, languages, and political boundaries, and to present work in multiple forms. It's a time of both/and rather than either/or. We will discuss and write about a range of contemporary print, digital, and performance works; students will also compose and publish/perform at least one single-authored or collaborative poem. Contemporary Poetry is one of a set of multimodal courses including Sound Poetry, Visual Poetry, Digital Poetics, and Material Poetics, investigating sensory and material poetic traditions in contemporary culture. All courses have creative, critical, research, and performance/publication commitments. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomore and above&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0816254</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31422</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E247-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>VIRGINIA WOOLF &amp; MODERN FICTION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Students will emerge from this class with a thorough overview of Woolf's life, world, and life's work. The heart of the course will be our study of Virginia Woolf's major novels: Jacob's Room, Mrs. Dalloway, To the Lighthouse, Orlando, and The Waves. However, our reading list will also include short stories, essays, and selections from her published letters and diaries. In particular, students can expect to become skilled readers of the stream of consciousness style of narration that characterizes Woolf's fiction and to engage with themes that run through much of her writing such as the creative process, modern subjectivity, sexuality, gender, domestic space, and war.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596127</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29036</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E254-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>NATIVE AMERICAN LITERATURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Literature is one facet of culture.  The significance of literature can be best understood in terms of the culture for which it springs, and the purpose is clear only when the reader understands and accepts the assumptions on which literature is based" (Paula Gunn Allen-Laguna Sioux poet). This course will explore value systems and aesthetics that are from very diverse Native cultures, focusing on the ways in which indigenousness relates to literature and storytelling. The critical methodologies developed by Native critics such as Gerald Vizenor  (Anishinaabe writer and scholar), and Craig Womack (Muscogee Creek-Cherokee author and professor of Native Studies) will enable us to study Native frameworks and new ways to regard literature/histories. We will explore questions such as can Native American theory/literature transform or challenge non-Native critical theoretical strategies. Our discussions, which may take a variety of directions, will also examine such issues as American Indian identities and communities as well as the impact of colonization on tribal peoples.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0709283</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24157</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E255-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>THE JEWISH NARRATIVE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Modern Jewish literary form and content developed from the 19th-century emancipation with its socialist, Zionist, and romantic options. We move from these roots to the satiric and elegiac voice of contemporary America. Authors studied will include Sholom Aleichem, Isaac Singer, Elie Wiesel, Bernard Malamud.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0004008</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31410</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E274-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>POST-WAR AMERICAN LITERATURE: NARRATING COUNTERCULTURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course will focus on the literary expression of American counterculture during the 1950s and 60s the so-called 'Beat' and 'Hippie' generations. The writers, artists, musicians, and bohemians who gave voice to counterculture during these two decades impacted not only literature and art, but also revolutionized social and political ideologies.  Their emphasis on individual freedom, spiritual liberation, and subcultural hipness, called on all Americans to define their "authentic" selves, to seek higher consciousnesses, and to resist the establishment's repressive mandate that we remain passive consumers rather than active creators. With literature as our guide, we'll begin by examining the Beat movement with its emphasis on spontaneity and the search for 'ITO' we'll then look at how Beat aesthetics and ideologies were adopted and politicized during the heyday of the Hippie movement; finally, we'll consider the impact of these earlier generations on later countercultural movements such as the Punks of the 70s and early 80s.  In the course of our reading, we'll consider the impact of cultural contexts and political motivations on the literature: the Cold War; McCarthyism; the rise of mass consumer culture and mass media; the Civil Rights and Anti-War movements; and shifting politics around gender and sexuality.  We'll also investigate how members of those groups already on the margins of dominant socio-political discourse-women, racial, ethnic, and sexual minorities-relate to the notion of counterculture.  Expect readings from Jack Kerouac, Allen Ginsberg, William Burroughs, Amiri Baraka, James Baldwin, Sylvia Plath, Tom Wolfe, Joseph Heller, Jim Carroll, Aaron Cometbus, and Hunter S. Thompson. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0937407</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29787</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E282-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ECOLOGICAL INVENTION IN EARLY AMERICA</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>How can looking back to early America help us think and act in our present age of ecological crisis? In this course, we will explore the roots of American ideas about nature, environmentalism, and ecology in early American literature, beginning in the pre-colonial era and ending in the late nineteenth century. In the process, we will study the wide-ranging ecological views of indigenous Americans, Euro-colonial unsettlers of North America, enslaved and emancipated African transplants, and the various inhabitants of the United States in its first century as a nation state. In particular, we will examine how the confluence of various cultures influenced ideas about the conservation and exploitation of the natural world to varying degrees. To do so, we will ask how early American environmental writers defined nature and what these definitions included and excluded. To what degree did human dominion over the natural world and its resources extend? Was America a place for farmer-settlers or backwoods hunters and traders? Was its vast wilderness a refuge for religious worship or the devil's territory? Were humans part of nature or distinct from it, and which people counted as fully human? Was slavery considered a natural or unnatural state? Were animals considered reasoning subjects, instinctual objects of scientific study, or merely animate natural resources? Along the way, we will also ask how nature writing developed as its own multimedia genre during the period, as well as how it influenced various other genres of imaginative literature.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1545266</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31419</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E309-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE> TRANSNATIONAL SPY &amp; DETECTIVE FICTION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course, besides revisiting the traditional narrative elements of spy and detective fiction, considers a selection of the increasing number of late twentieth- and twenty-first-century transnational, diasporic, postcolonial, and minority/ethnic authors from around the world who adapt spy and detective fiction conventions for the purpose of social critique. In focusing on issues related to identity, "culture," ethics, human rights, justice, and knowledge construction narrated by these fictions, we will examine carefully, for example, the figure of the spy or detective as outsider to and observer of society as well as, in the works at issue here, frequently an immigrant or cultural or social "other." In the process, we will also engage questions central to reading, interpreting, and comparing fiction in a global context.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000177</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29788</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E310-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>NARRATIVES FROM AROUND THE WORLD</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>We will study contemporary world narratives-fiction and film-which have been published or produced within the last ten to twenty years. In order to keep up with current work, the specific content of the course will change each year. We will study fiction and film in English and in translation (subtitled). In the past, the work of Salman Rushdie, Mario Vargas Llosa, Kamila Shamsie, Tash Aw, Shahrnush Parsipur, and Haruki Murakami has been included.  In addition to the assigned reading, we will screen and discuss an international film each week. By the end of the semester, thematic and stylistic links as well as the uniqueness of certain work, like Kore-eda Hirokazu's &lt;I&gt;After Life&lt;/I&gt;, Oppenheimer's &lt;I&gt;The Act of Killing&lt;/I&gt;, or Roy Andersson's &lt;I&gt;You, the Living&lt;/I&gt;, will become apparent. Short analytic/interpretive essays in response to the fiction and film and thoughtful class participation are required.&lt;BR&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0089628</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29789</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E310-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>NARRATIVES FROM AROUND THE WORLD</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>We will study contemporary world narratives-fiction and film-which have been published or produced within the last ten to twenty years. In order to keep up with current work, the specific content of the course will change each year. We will study fiction and film in English and in translation (subtitled). In the past, the work of Salman Rushdie, Mario Vargas Llosa, Kamila Shamsie, Tash Aw, Shahrnush Parsipur, and Haruki Murakami has been included.  In addition to the assigned reading, we will screen and discuss an international film each week. By the end of the semester, thematic and stylistic links as well as the uniqueness of certain work, like Kore-eda Hirokazu's &lt;I&gt;After Life&lt;/I&gt;, Oppenheimer's &lt;I&gt;The Act of Killing&lt;/I&gt;, or Roy Andersson's &lt;I&gt;You, the Living&lt;/I&gt;, will become apparent. Short analytic/interpretive essays in response to the fiction and film and thoughtful class participation are required.&lt;BR&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0089628</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31368</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E314-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>IRISH DRAMA/IRISH FILM</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course will engage enactments of Irish drama in the twentieth/twenty-first century, from Yeats to Denis Johnston, O'Casey, Synge, Heaney, Keene, Behan, McDonagh, Friel and the crucial contributions of women playwrights to this canon, from Lady Gregory to Anne Devlin, Katy Hayes, Una Troy and others.  The course will supplement these readings with selections from Irish cinema, from Neil Jordan and Jim Sheridan to Roddy Doyle, Terry George, Alan Parker, Michael McDonagh and recent documentary work from Ireland, as well as a discussion of the Republican muralist tradition as street drama.  Students will engage these texts through analysis, discussion, and short essays, culminating in a longer essay to more fully explore central issues and cap the course.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1598038</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>24141</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E326-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BIRDS IN BOOKS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>We begin with a study of the bird painters, illustrators and photographers, most notably, of course, John James Audubon, and continue with the symbolic bird of poetry and literature, such as &lt;i&gt;Green Mansions &lt;/i&gt; by W.H. Hudson--the bird as woman--and examine the bird as omen and warning--the ecological and environmental indicator of human fate.  Our books include such recent essays and memoirs as Jonathan Safran Foer's &lt;i&gt;Eating Animals&lt;/i&gt; -- an indictment of the poultry industry and a plea for vegetarianism--and also the arguments both personal/subjective and yet also scientific for the intelligence of birds such as the bestseller books &lt;i&gt;Alex: The Parrot that Owned Me&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Wesley the Barn Owl,&lt;/i&gt; in which birds appear not so much as pets but rather as companion creatures who share our destiny and condition.&lt;BR&gt; Our course will include actual birdwatching during times of migration or nest-building, either locally within the borders of our campus world, or beyond its frontiers.  Migration has always meant the crossing of national barriers, and therefore a promise of peace and order despite the turmoil under the skies.  We read, we watch, and we design projects relevant to the various meanings of birds to be found in books.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0004008</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29790</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E333-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LIT: THE INDIAN SUBCONTINENT</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>There is a long history of literature on the Indian subcontinent, and while Bangladesh, India, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka have different histories since partition, their literary history and continued development are intertwined.  This course will look at the literature of the region, including works by writers in exile.  Writers examined may include Anand, Desai, Hamid, Narayan, Nasrin, and Rushdie.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0452503</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29009</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E349-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FAMILY NARRATIVES</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Tolstoy's famous opening sentence of &lt;I&gt;Anna Karenina&lt;/I&gt; reminds us that families provide a lot of good material for fiction and film narratives. "All happy families resemble one another," he writes, "but each unhappy family is unhappy in its own way." This seminar will take a look at unhappy and happy families alike and will consider alternative or surrogate family structures and definitions of home. Contemporary writers like Jhumpa Lahiri, Michael Cunningham, Philip Roth, Chang-rae Lee, Jonathan Safran Foer, and Jeffrey Eugenides, just to name a few, take us inside homes where identities are formed and where they clash. We will also study family portraiture in film to extend our understanding of the subject's narrative possibilities.  Students must be prepared to participate in class, must know how to read narratives closely, and must be able to write specific and detailed papers each week in response to assigned material.  Research outside of the class material is expected.   &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt; Open to sophomore and above.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0089628</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31366</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E351-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>DARK MATTER: AN INTRODUCTION TO RACE, GENDER, AND SPECULATIVE FICTION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Greg Tate has said that "Black people live the estrangement that science fiction writers imagine." This course takes up the nexus of intersections between black history and the radical black imagination that is commonly called Afrofuturism, focusing in particular on figurations of Africa as a space of science fictional possibility from both sides of the Atlantic. If Afrofuturism has been, as Kodwo Eshun has said, "a program for recovering the histories of counter-futures created in a century hostile to Afrodiasporic projection," how do these writers, filmmakers and artists of the African diaspora reshape the very definition of who and/or what qualifies as human? What can these visions tell us about living in a black body in the present? How can Afrofuturism be used to critique racial asymmetries in the present and to imagine as-yet-unrealized, free black futures? From literature to film to music to art we will trace Afrofuturism across the twenty-first century cultural landscape. Using Afrofuturism, critical race studies, and queer theory, we will investigate the ways that science fiction's disruption of race, gender, and sexuality as stable categories offers radical models for our present and possible futures.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1596193</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31365</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E383-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BLACK HEROES, SUPERHEROES, AND MUTANTS FROM THE 60S TO TODAY: REPRESENTATIONS AND METAPHOR FOR BLACKNESS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Launched originally as Timely Comics in 1939, Marvel Comics has always reflected, commented on, and shaped the real world. This course will focus on Marvel Comics creation of visually black hero and  superheroes as well as metaphors for blackness during the Black Civil Rights/ Black Power Movements-specifically Luke Cage, Black Panther, and the X-Men, -in order to consider how Marvel mobilized the racial and colonial unrest of the period to imagine and in some cases imaginatively contain trajectories of black political insurgency. Because all three of these figures/comic books have re-emerged over the last several years, after attempting to understand the work as original construction in its original context, we will look at Marvel's contemporary filmic articulations of blackness to consider whether they represent the same or different projects regarding race and colonialism. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;But what I write and how I write is done in order to save my own life. And I mean that literally. For me literature is a way of knowing that I am not hallucinating, that whatever I feel/know is.&lt;/I&gt; &lt;br&gt;  -Barbara Christian: The Race For Theory. &lt;br&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to sophomores and above. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1541782</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>25838</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E421-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ADVANCED POETRY WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The Advanced Poetry Workshop is an intensive project-based poetry workshop for students with previous workshop experience and a portfolio of revised work on which to build. The course centers on workshop: peer critique by students with previous practice in poetry writing, and the shared goal of completing a semester-long publication/performance project. Students are expected to have a strong commitment to active participation in contemporary poetry as readers, writers, curators, performers, and audience. Teaching and learning methodologies include close reading of exemplary texts, experimentation with forms, revision, online/print publication, and performance. Texts will include poetry collections published in 2019 and 2020, as selected by students and instructor. The workshop welcomes work in any language and from any tradition of poetry. To the greatest extent possible, the work should speak for itself. But mediation, translation, contextualization also play a vital role.  &lt;BR&gt; Prerequisite: LAS-E411 Beginning Poetry Writing Workshop, or equivalent experience.  &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt;Open to sophomore and above. &lt;BR&gt; Permission of Instructor required. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0816254</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>25083</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E422-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ADVANCED FICTION WRITING WKSHP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>The advanced workshop assumes that students have some experience with writing fiction and are ready for an environment that will challenge them to hone, revise, and distill their craft. A writer begins inspired by dreams, language, a face in a crowd. But inspiration is only the beginning of a writer's work. In this course we'll study form, theme, voice, language, character, and plot. We'll also read and talk about stories by masters of the craft. The aim of the workshop is to help you discover what your stories want to be and fulfill the promise of your original vision. &lt;BR&gt; &lt;i&gt;Prerequisite: LAS-E412: Beginning Fiction Writing Workshop or equivalent experience. &lt;BR&gt; Open to sophomore and above.  &lt;BR&gt; Permission of Instructor required.&lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1365402</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29792</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E522-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BEFORE AND AFTER "MAN": OBJECTS, ANIMALS, SEX, AND RACE IN GENRES OF THE POST-HUMAN</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course explores the human as a temporally specific and, perhaps, obsolescing philosophical concept. Emerging most cogently in the European Enlightenment, humans materialize as the center of their own concerns, i.e. humanism, through a set of binary oppositions that include human/god, human/animal, human/savage, hu(man)/woman, human/machine, subject/object etc. Post-humanism, broadly conceived, seeks to mark, blur, upend, and/or abolish the distinction or relationship between the opposed terms of these binaries. This course begins by attempting to account for how the human/Man came to prominence during the economic, social and geopolitical conditions of the 17th and 18th century in order to understand the threads of thought that contemporary genres of Post-humanisms attempt to unravel: such as animal studies, object oriented ontology, AI studies, and feminist and black studies in the subject of "Man." The course then turns to these various subgenres in order to think through post-humanism's ethical, political, and social stakes in our contemporary moment.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1541782</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31363</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E522-02</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>BEFORE AND AFTER "MAN": OBJECTS, ANIMALS, SEX, AND RACE IN GENRES OF THE POST-HUMAN</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course explores the human as a temporally specific and, perhaps, obsolescing philosophical concept. Emerging most cogently in the European Enlightenment, humans materialize as the center of their own concerns, i.e. humanism, through a set of binary oppositions that include human/god, human/animal, human/savage, hu(man)/woman, human/machine, subject/object etc. Post-humanism, broadly conceived, seeks to mark, blur, upend, and/or abolish the distinction or relationship between the opposed terms of these binaries. This course begins by attempting to account for how the human/Man came to prominence during the economic, social and geopolitical conditions of the 17th and 18th century in order to understand the threads of thought that contemporary genres of Post-humanisms attempt to unravel: such as animal studies, object oriented ontology, AI studies, and feminist and black studies in the subject of "Man." The course then turns to these various subgenres in order to think through post-humanism's ethical, political, and social stakes in our contemporary moment.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1541782</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>26952</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E718-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>NATURAL HISTORY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This seminar has two primary goals:  &lt;BR&gt; 1. To engage critically with natural history as a literary and visual art form and with its history as a scientific practice.  &lt;BR&gt; 2. To collaborate on projects and experiments that employ digital and analog methods for analyzing, interpreting, archiving, curating, and creating visual and literary works of natural history. Throughout the semester, we will visit local museums, labs, archives, and field sites to facilitate these goals.  &lt;BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt; Natural history is a crucial genre for understanding the origins of modern environmentalism, the history of science, discourses of race, and the nature of European imperialism. As an artistic and epistemological practice, natural history enjoyed the height of its popularity during the early modern and enlightenment periods, as European explorers, traders, and colonizers endeavored to classify, catalog, explain, and exploit the diverse flora and fauna all over the planet. In the process, they encountered (and often ignored or stole from) the complex folk biology of various indigenous cultures. Especially in the Americas, natural historical knowledge production depended on the collaboration of various cultures within profoundly uneven power dynamics: European explorers and creolized American naturalists, political leaders and ordinary citizens, amateur collectors and professional theorists, men and women, slaveholders and enslaved people, and Euro-colonial traders and indigenous Americans. Furthermore, early naturalists were polymaths --scientists, philosophers, political leaders, artists, writers, collectors, and traders --before the stratification of the modern sciences into disciplines that took place during the nineteenth century. As science became a more professional and specialized endeavor, natural history evolved into various forms of amateur field science, environmental art, and nature writing, an evolution this course will actively examine through reading, conversation, and practice. As such, our course materials will range from classical antiquity to the present and cover a large variety of written forms and artistic mediums.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1545266</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>27861</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E761-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>SEM: GLOBAL ENGLISHES</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This seminar attempts to do two things: first, we examine the global careers of the English language and the literatures written in it from their period of ascendance during the height of British colonialism in the late-19th century to their proliferation in the postcolonial present to argue for a concept of multiple "Englishes" in place of one dominant, normative, authentic 'English';second, we explore the hypothesis that the discourse of "Global Englishes" is not just constituted in writing and literature as most scholars have argued but also through everyday performance, and often through spoken forms. So, a discussion of the cultural politics of speaking and listening across different sonic media will supplement the regular study of selected fiction, nonfiction, plays, poetry, films, television, and music. Topics discussed will include variations in the uses of literary English, translations and adaptations, varieties of spoken Englishes, accents and code-switching, multilingualism in literary texts, etc. Historical and theoretical contexts will include colonialism and postcolonialism, economic and cultural globalization, identity politics, exile and migration, literary prizes, circulation and readership, etc. Not surprisingly, most of the authors we will read are from ex-colonies of the British Empire which now have thriving English language literary and cultural traditions of their own, like India and Pakistan, Nigeria and South Africa, Canada and Australia, Ireland and the Caribbean region. Since the United Kingdom's and the United States' Englishes, even though dominant, are still part of 'the global' we will read some representative texts from Scotland or Wales, for instance, as well as "US ethnic literatures." Authors may include Rudyard Kipling, Rokeya Sakhawat Hossain, G V Desani, Salman Rushdie, J M Coetzee, Jean Rhys, Wole Soyinka, Michle Lalonde, Derek Walcott, Brian Friel, Amitav Ghosh, Arundhati Roy, Mohsin Hamid, M. NourbeSe Philip, Irvine Welsh, Caroline Bergvall, and Junot Diaz. Open to sophomore and above. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Open to sophomore and above.&lt;/I&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1115363</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>30239</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-E798-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>SEM: "TO PLOUGH VAN DIEMEN'S LAND": CONVICTS IN AUSTRALIAN LITERATURE AND CULTURE</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Australia's literary culture is intertwined with the history of the First Fleet and the convicts who were the first Europeans to live on the continent. This seminar examines the convict in literature and its continuing reverberations in Australian culture. We will begin by looking at the poems of the convict Francis MacNamara-"Frank the Poet"-then move on the Marcus Clarke's epic about convict life, For the Term of His Natural Life. We will then look at some contemporary Australian literature which looks back at Transportation and its after-effects.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2020SP</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS></COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0452503</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32052</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-W033-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>PALEOGRAPHY: WESTERN HANDWRITTEN LETTERFORMS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This Liberal Arts Elective is a hands-on investigation of the development of Latin handwritten letters from about 200 BCE to about 1500 CE, analyzing scripts and script families from Roman cursive and monumental letters to the Renaissance letters that were the basis of most modern fonts. The emphasis of the course is on dynamic analysis of letters as written rather than static forms, though we will also explore the implications of the Platonic and later organic/evolutionary models that are the traditional means for understanding the history of letterforms.  Students will master a basic Italic hand; study and write versions of a dozen or more historical scripts originally executed with styli, brushes, and reed, quill, and metal pens; make pens from river reeds and other materials (and write with them); and investigate the properties of papyrus, wood, vellum, and paper as writing surfaces. The class will visit at least one museum, spend extensive time outside of class practicing letters, and write two papers involving the historical contexts, paleographic characteristics, and calligraphic/graphic procedures for particular handwritten manuscripts. Although all the scripts studied were originally written right-handed, left-handed students have excelled in the course.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0303681</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>27864</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-W050-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>THEATER PRODUCTION WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Professional actor/director Fred Sullivan (Trinity Repertory Company/Gamm Theatre/ Commonwealth Shakespeare resident artist and RISD Acting Workshop instructor) will guide a company of student actors, designers, stage managers through a workshop process of producing a live play for the stage, culminating in a two public performances of the production. Students in this course will be asked to: rehearse and perform assigned roles; accept assigned duties on graphic, projection and property/costume design, construction and stage management crews; commit to a flexible rehearsal schedule outside of class meetings; and pursue a guided study of the dramaturgical and production elements of the play or plays being produced. Under consideration for this Wintersession production is a selection of short plays by modern masters and original work. The structure of the selected play will be analyzed for its themes and historic context as well. The play will furthermore be examined for its unique performance techniques and production requirements. Sign up, put on some comfortable clothes and come to the first class ready to play.  </COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0103295</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>29794</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-W077-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>FILM INVESTIGATIONS</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>We explore both narrative and nonfiction films and videotapes.  We write essays to establish critical standards.  We produce personal film essays by raiding the family album of photos and movies. The course thus aims to combine the humanist perspective with a recognition of actual production.  We draw our films from many sources. We draw our readings from a wide range of film journals and establish a shelf of reserve reading material in our library. These sources are incorporated into our discussions and reports. The course requires a class presentation about a film shown and a visual project in film or slides.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0623289</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32277</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAEL-W127-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ENVIRONMENTAL HUMANITIES RESEARCH SEMINAR</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Practitioners in the Environmental Humanities (EH) engage in disciplinary and cross-disciplinary research in the humanities to think about representation, meaning, value, ethics, and power in relation to environmental questions, issues, and crises.  EH offers a capacious umbrella under which to gather inquiry in anthropology, art and design, critical animal studies, cultural studies, film studies, history, literary studies, philosophy, and visual studies, among other disciplines, methodologies, and modes.  As Emily O'Gorman and her colleagues write in their introduction to "Teaching the Environmental Humanities: International Perspectives and Practices," EH is "grounded in the growing recognition that diverse human understandings about, and activities in, the environment are critical factors in making sense of, and responsibly inhabiting, a dynamic more-than-human-world. [.] Work in EH seeks to develop and support alternative framings, approaches, and solutions that operate outside the dichotomized understandings of society and the environment which have underpinned diverse forms of colonialism, militarism, globalism, extractivism, and erasure.  Living as we are in the midst of these violent global transformations, work in EH seeks to find modes of addressing environmental change that take seriously issues of justice, inequality, and oppression, and that value and support diversities of all kinds."  Students in the Environmental Humanities Research Seminar will engage in guided and independent liberal arts-based research in the environmental humanities in order to contextualize, extend, and/or refine an existing project or to develop a new project.  The project under development could be either a liberal-arts based project or it could be a studio-based project that would be deepened through liberal-arts based research.  The seminar will include reading and discussion that gives all participants a common vocabulary for liberal arts-based research in the environmental humanities, but each student will develop and pursue an individualized research program.  In addition to deep curiosity about one's subject matter, receptivity to the messiness of the research process, and a willingness to support other classmates in their research, this class requires excellent time management skills.  Assignments will include: library-based research, an annotated bibliography, reflective writing, a final paper, and a final presentation.  Students need to obtain instructor permission to enroll in this course. &lt;BR&gt;&lt;I&gt; Permission of Instructor required. &lt;BR&gt; Email nmerola@risd.edu to apply to enroll. &lt;/i&gt;</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0990940</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>31364</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-W261-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>LITERATURE BETWEEN HABIT AND ADDICTION</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>n depictions of addiction, literature imagines ecstatic pleasure, intense suffering, and spiritual revelation. In this course, students become familiar with the vocabulary and narrative forms associated with distinct strains of thought about addiction. The readings consist of fiction, film, and life writing from the early 19th Century to the 21st Century, and consider how models of addiction-moral, medical, and more-both develop chronologically and recur. Authors studied may include Thomas DeQuincey, George Eliot, Edgar Allan Poe, Jean Stafford, James Baldwin, Mary Gaitskill, Suzan-Lori Parks, Danny Boyle, and Augusten Burroughs. Students write a series of short essays as well as a longer final project that combines critical analysis and life writing.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>2000073</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32103</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-W359-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>CRADLE WILL ROCK ON</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course asks students to travel back to the 1930s and contextualize the various artistic and cultural movements that comprised the Federal Theater Project and the WPA arts projects.  The course will revolve around the 1999 film by Tim Robbins, Cradle Will Rock, and the Marc Blitzstein original, as well as supplementary materials researched by the students involving any aspect of the film, from Brechtian and Documentary drama to Mexican muralism to labor issues to race and gender resistance to LGBTQ histories and on.  Students will research toward a final artistic project that comprises the requirement for the course.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1598038</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>27866</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-W379-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>MAJOR DEVELOPMENTS IN QUEER FILM, 1990-2018</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>This course focuses on the intersectionalities of race and queer subjectivities in queer cinema. We will trace this development from the historical cinematic 1990s of New Queer Cinema (NQC), an era that encompasses an explosion of "gay film visibility," to an exploration of present day queer cinema and the ways in which queer representations and queer identities are portrayed. We will study the stylistic developments and controversies of queer film, examining major innovations and changes as compared to films from the NQC era. Such questions as what's at stake in films that contest and re-imagine new queer subjectivities will be addressed during the course.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0709283</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32051</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-W388-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>ROCKUMENTARY</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>Visions of youthful utopia in Monterey Pop (1968) give way to violence and mayhem in Gimmie Shelter (Rolling Stones, 1970). Martin Scorsese offers an epilogue to an era in The Last Waltz (The Band, 1978). Madonna sells herself in Truth or Dare (1991) and Metallica undergoes group therapy in Some Kind of Monster (2004). Rock documentaries are as much about the social and political state of America as they are about music and musicians. In this course, we will explore the visual language and cultural history of the rockumentary film genre. Topics for discussion will include: documentary and cinema Veriti narrative forms; the troubled notion of documentary "truth"; music as commercial product; fandom and the cult of celebrity; and the rise of MTV. Students should be prepared to participate in class discussion, attend film screenings, complete critical readings, and hone their analytical writing skills.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0937407</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32099</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-W432-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>SHORT STORY WRITING WORKSHOP</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>In this writing workshop, we will explore the short story form, working to put into words what we--as individual readers--hope to find in it. We will consider what makes a story a story, while acknowledging that it is often something ineffable, indefinable. We will read from a range of contemporary and classic writers and will also read essays on craft. A significant amount of class time will be devoted to peer workshops. At the end of the term, students will be expected to submit a portfolio comprised of reflections, writing exercises, and completed stories.</COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>1425658</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
  <COURSE>
   <COURSESYNONYM>32050</COURSESYNONYM>
   <COURSENAME>LAS-W486-01</COURSENAME>
   <COURSETITLE>THE COOKBOOK: THE RHETORIC OF RECIPES</COURSETITLE>
   <COURSEDESC>"The Cookbook: The Rhetoric of Recipes" is a course designed to look at the form and rhetoric of cookbooks. Cookbooks are their own distinct genre. There are rules that must be followed, though the range of possibilities are multitudinous. A cookbook entirely about bugs? Sure. A cookbook on gelatin desserts? In the 1960s there were dozens. But a cookbook ostensibly is both tantalizing and informative. It aims to make the reader want to eat the dish that it introduces, and it gives clear instruction about how to produce that dish. The course begins by looking medieval recipes, many of them found online at Cooking in the Archive. From there the course moves to looking at the culinary essays of Alexandre Balthazar Laurent Grimod de La Reynire and Jean Anthelme Brillat-Savarin, the founders of culinary writing. Then we move to MFK Fisher and James Beard, before looking at Julia Child and Jacques Pepin and the rise of the celebrity chef. In the course students will be asked to deconstruct recipes. What makes a recipe successful? The rhetoric of cookbooks is an art, just as is poetry or memoir writing. Some cookbooks are literature, others are pulp. Over the course of five weeks, students will begin to learn how to create a recipe that both instructs and entices. They will learn how personality enters a cookbook, and how something like Marcus Samuelsson's The Soul of a New Cuisine is ultimately more about the writer than the recipes. By the course's end, each student will produce their own cookbook.    </COURSEDESC>
   <COURSETERM>2021WS</COURSETERM>
   <COURSECREDITS>3.00</COURSECREDITS>
   <COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>UG</COURSEACADEMICLEVEL>
   <COURSEFACULTY>0452503</COURSEFACULTY>
  </COURSE>
</DEPARTMENT>
</ROOT>
